Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Every time I see you,
I remember the betrayal
your father did to our family.
Just pretend that
we haven't met at all.
Juanito! Juanito!
It's mother!
I didn't think
we'll see each other again
after we bid our goodbye in Sugbu.
I wanted to
fix
and get something back here.
And I'm hoping...
It's not too late.
I want to show you
how pure my intentions are.
Don't worry.
I'll tell Father
that the wedding
with Leandro will not happen.
I am here
to know you.
That Carmelita
has decided
to be a servant of the church.
I will give you
more time to think.
Carmelita.
I'm hoping...
You'd still choose
me in the end.
I will never forget this night.
The night
when the firefly found...
The woman he was dreaming of.
Is it true you are marrying
Maria off to Governor Flores?
Carmelita,
ask forgiveness from Father.
Esmeralda, I command
you to stop this right now!
I apologize, Miss Josefina.
I will only follow Don Alejandro.
And he specifically told me
to watch over Miss Carmelita's punishment.
Wait...
Esmeralda!
I beg you.
Have mercy on Carmelita.
Esmeralda, I beg you.
Raise your arms, Miss.
I'm alright, Josefina.
I can do it.
I remember,
when Maria and I were kids...
The love between Father
and Mother wasn't deep.
Because they, too, were
only arranged in marriage.
Even though they had children...
We can really feel
that love is lacking.
And when Mother gave birth to you...
Everything changed.
Because of your
joyful and affectionate nature...
You pulled them closer.
And they learned to love each other.
Because of you,
our family became whole.
I can sense that,
I will be the reason why
the Montecarlos family might fall apart.
I understand.
You are becoming your own woman.
But I hope you won't let
our family fall apart again.
Miss,
it was Don Alejandro's strict orders.
You cannot stand up from here
until he says so.
Carmelita!
Carmelita.
I will ask Father for forgiveness.
Come here, stand up.
Father, please have mercy!
Father, please have mercy.
Get out of here for now.
Didn't I tell you to kneel on salt?!
You're disobeying me again, Carmelita!
And you, Josefina!
You must learn to discipline your sister!
Father,
forgive me!
But Carmelita have something to say to you.
I have no time for this! Get out!
Mother, please help us.
Stop this insolence!
You brought shame into our family!
You tainted my name in
front of Gobernadorcillo Flores!
How long will you and Carmelita
keep causing me problems?!
First thing tomorrow,
You will have that child aborted.
Maria is pregnant?
Father, please have mercy...
I can't bear to lose this child in my womb.
I can't do it, Father.
I can't bear to lose this
child in my womb, Father.
I am begging you, please, Father!
I won’t allow your child with that gardener
to be born into this world!
You will have that child aborted.
And you will marry Gobernadorcillo Flores.
- Father!
- Maria! Please stand up.
Father, just let me
give birth to this child!
I will still marry Gobernadorcillo Flores.
Father, I beg you!
I won't have a disgraced daughter.
And Governor Flores wouldn't accept a wife
who has a child with another man!
That is why that child must
die for the sake of our family!
Father! Father, I beg you.
Please let Maria's child live.
Don't force her to marry Governor Flores.
I will do it.
Because...
I'm ready to marry Leandro.
Carmelita?
How are you feeling?
The herbal medicine you
applied to my knees was effective.
The pain was lessened.
How's Maria?
I just came from her bedroom.
Father ordered her to stay there
until it's decided when
she'll go to Laguna.
To the home of Aunt Rosario.
Why is she going to Laguna?
I think Father wants to hide her far away.
It's a great shame if people
find out she's pregnant
without getting married.
What if her baby gets aborted?
But you promised
that you'd get married
to Leandro, didn't you?
Do you remember?
When Leandro went to court you?
Governor Flores requested
to be married to Maria.
But it didn't push through.
Because he was so focused
on your wedding to Leandro.
But when it was stopped too,
Father couldn't do anything.
He has to agree to what
Governor Flores wants.
To be married to Maria.
I did the right thing.
Maria was put into this situation
because I wanted to be with Juanito.
I need to help her.
Father, Mother.
I’m one of those chosen by Mother Olivia
to lead the prayer in the plaza.
It's on All Souls’ Day.
I am very happy for you, dear.
Mother Olivia has chosen well
in giving you that responsibility.
Hey, congrats!
I mean, I'm happy for you, Josefina.
Alejandro!
What was that?
You scum!
Get off me!
I said get off!
Mr. Raul?
Father?
Father!
They didn't mean for it to
happen, so just let them be!
Alejandro!
It's not good for your
heart if you become angry.
Have you no shame, Alejandro?
What authority do you have
to have my son arrested and imprisoned?
Alejandro!
Father! Do not hurt Mr. Raul!
Father! I'm begging you!
Stand up!
You have the nerve to
raise your voice at me?
Since you already know
that I will kick you out of here.
Beat him up to make
sure he learned his lesson!
No!
Please don't, Father!
Stop!
Father, I'm begging you!
Do not hurt Mr. Raul!
- Please, stop!
- Carmelita, be quiet.
Your father might get angry at you again.
Call Leandro.
We need to help them.
Where's Eduardo?
I heard Father had him arrested in town
under General Seleno.
And I heard he was accused
of planning something
sinister against Maria.
Throw that old man into prison!
I will await Gobernadorcillo Flores' order.
On what to do to finish off this scum.
That's enough.
- That's enough.
- Remember this!
I swear.
I will get my revenge.
I will return all of
this to you, Alejandro!
Is it how you repay me for
accepting you and your children
here, at our house?
I gave you honorable work and a good life!
If threats and curses are
your payment for that...
Then it is just fitting for me
to take your life as payment!
- Father, no!
- Alejandro, that's enough.
You only gave us food and shelter!
But not once
did you ever treat us as equals
nor gave us the right compensation!
That is why we owe you nothing!
Take him away!
Carmelita,
I know you're still thinking about Juanito.
Do you want to send him a letter?
I can ask Mother Olivia for help.
Honestly, Josefina...
I still don't know
what to say to him.
That’s why I can’t bring
myself to write him a letter.
I can't tell him that
I won't be able to fulfill my promise.
And if ever we meet...
I wouldn't know what to do.
I cannot face him anymore.
Carmelita,
even I’m worried
that Juanito might think you
don’t care about him anymore.
Even after waiting for you patiently.
But I think he also
deserves to know the truth
about what's happening with you.
And why you're doing
it for our family's sake.
Avoiding him won't solve the problem.
And if you don't clear things up with him,
you might leave him confused.
He could be scarred for life.
Josefina is right.
It will be unfair to Juanito if I just
leave him hanging without any explanation.
He doesn't deserve that.
He might even curse me.
Maria?
Carmelita?
Carmelita, is that you?
Yes, it's me.
How are you?
Carmelita, where is Eduardo?
What did Father do to Mr. Raul?
It might affect her baby if I
tell her Eduardo's in prison
and that Mr. Raul almost
got beaten to death.
I shouldn't have asked you that.
I know Father won't rest
until they were all punished.
Maria...
I'm sorry.
If I only agreed to marry Leandro...
Then maybe you wouldn't be -
you wouldn't be arranged to
get married to Governor Flores.
And Father would just
leave you with your child.
Because of me...
Your child with Eduardo was put in danger.
No.
Carmelita, that's not true.
This wasn't your fault.
Eduardo and I are at fault.
If only
we didn't do something
we would just regret in the end...
It's all my fault.
It's all because of me.
Maria, your child with
Eduardo will never be a mistake.
That child is part of our family.
My family.
Blood of our blood.
And that child will be loved.
Keep the faith, Maria.
I will do something about this.
Thank you very much, Carmelita.
Carmelita!
Let's go.
Josefina?
Maria!
There's just something
I need to tell Carmelita.
What is it?
- What happened?
- I have some bad news.
Father ordered to have Mr. Raul killed.
What?!
No!
That can't happen!
Maria...
Mr. Raul is held at the
back of the hacienda.
But tomorrow, he
will be taken to the
mountain to be executed
by the civil guards.
Josefina, quickly.
Father and Mother might come back soon.
The key!
Do you think the guards are asleep?
I think the sleeping draught
we gave them is effective.
Let's go.
How did Raul escape?!
I know somebody helped him!
Who's responsible for this?!
Is it you?!
Forgive me for speaking
my mind, Don Alejandro.
But I believe none of your
workers will dare oppose you.
And I also know you’re aware
that you can’t punish whoever they are.
What are you trying to say, Esmeralda?
Forgive me, Don Alejandro.
But if we will be objective here...
Only Miss Carmelita has
the guts to oppose you
and go against your commands.
Your child is stubborn.
She rarely listen to your orders.
She doesn't listen to your advice.
And most of all,
she's too determined for her own good.
Excuse my intrusion, Esmeralda.
You should know your
place in this household.
Carmelita, come over here.
In this case...
Disobeying my orders as
the Governor’s right-hand man
carries the same punishment...
For everyone.
And even though you are my daughter,
you cannot escape punishment.
Father,
it is not fair to blame Carmelita
just because of your
previous misunderstandings.
Miss Josefina,
you may be also complicit
in Miss Carmelita's actions.
Because you helped Mr. Raul escape.
How did that old scum manage to escape you?
I didn't have anything to
do with it, Don Alejandro.
I do not know who put
sleeping draughts in their food.
Also, I just suddenly saw
the guardia civil unconscious.
So you're saying someone else did it
and is making you look guilty instead?
Search everywhere!
Find the key!
I'm sorry, Esmeralda.
I don't want anyone else to
take the fall for what we did,
but I have to save my future family.
Good morning, Carmelita.
This is for you.
Thank you.
Your eyes look sad.
Are you alright?
It's Maria.
I heard of what happened to Maria.
My Father told me.
How are you?
I have no problems with
the new soldiers we're training.
And I am also glad that
Natasha is now back from Spain.
How about Helena?
Helena is still in Spain.
There is...
A young Spanish man from a prominent family
who wants to marry her.
I'm quite saddened
that you and Helena's friendship was lost.
But,
I am hopeful
you two will patch things up.
And I hope,
our relationship won't get affected.
Relationship?
Are we not...
Already arranged to get married, Carmelita?
Gosh!
I'm in a relationship with
both Juanito and Leandro.
I'm not even aware that I'm a two-timer.
Is that so?
Aren't things going too quickly?
Too quick or not,
it is still love, isn't it?
Also,
we quickly became a
couple before, didn't we?
Carmelita...
I know you're aware.
Since the start,
I have been charmed by your doe eyes...
And sweet smiles.
From the beginning,
my heart has already fallen for you.
That's why I hope you will accept my love.
That I wholeheartedly offer you.
I accept your love, Leandro.
Is that true, Carmelita?
We feel the same way?
Can I?
Can I embrace you?
There's a bug!
My love, I was just kidding.
I just want to make you laugh.
Leandro, it wasn't a nice joke!
You know I'm scared of bugs and animals.
Forgive me, my love.
Don't worry, I won't ever do it again.
Come.
Sit down.
Let me make up to you.
Is this?...
Your favorite.
Pinakbet.
Thank you.
Once your parents know
about our relationship,
I will take you to this
fine restaurant in town.
They have the most delicious
Pinakbet I have ever tasted.
That's a promise?
Promise.
Carmelita...
What kind of life do you want for yourself?
I want a big family.
And I want to see them all play around.
I will teach them how to read.
While you
will be working nearby.
So that in the evening,
we will have dinner together.
And when midnight comes,
I will kiss your forehead.
And I will whisper to your ear,
"Thank you, my love."
Because of you,
I was able to live the life I
have always been dreaming of.
I will love you,
every hour,
every second.
And every tomorrow.
Thank you.
Carmelita, are you alright?
I'm fine.
I'll just take a quick nap.
Careful.
Carmelita, dear.
Were you able to talk to General Leandro?
Did he leave already -
Carmelita?
Why do you look so pale?
Go and rest in your bedroom.
You haven't eaten breakfast too.
I will send it up to you.
Carmelita?
You haven't touched your breakfast.
You will not recover
your strength that way.
What is happening to you?
Your nausea is worse than Maria's.
Wait...
Don't tell me you're--
I am not pregnant.
Juanito respects me too much.
We can't say for sure.
As they say,
when two lovers get
caught up in the moment,
nothing could ever stop it!
Josefina,
what is Father's plan for Maria?
When will he bring Maria to Aunt Rosario?
I still don't know.
But from what I've heard,
Father wants to find Mr. Raul first.
So that he can be punished
together with Eduardo.
But first, you must eat.
Your back is drenched in sweat.
Can you pass me the wash cloth?
Carmelita?
I just noticed this now.
You have a birthmark on your nape?
Gosh! Carmelita doesn't
have any birthmarks.
No, that's not a birthmark.
It's a scar, Josefina.
I was wounded before and...
I scratched it too hard that's
why it turned into a scar.
- Mother.
- So, you're already awake, dear.
Here.
I brought you some medicine.
This will help you feel better.
And alleviate your nausea.
Thank you, Mother.
You are much welcome.
By the way,
your Father and I will
leave tomorrow night.
He was tasked by Gobernadorcillo Flores
to check the harvested grain in town.
That might take well into the morning
before we finish checking everything.
Please take care.
Alright, I'll leave the two of you.
Take care of your sister, alright?
Yes, Mother.
Here. Eat your lunch.
Carmelita!
Juanito?
I'm sorry.
It took me awhile to get here.
Ignacio and I had some
difficulties borrowing a boat
to get here in San Alfonso.
Boat?
Why didn't you travel by ship?
I'll take you away, Carmelita.
Let's elope somewhere
your Father wouldn't find.
When I received your letter,
I didn't hesistate to follow you here.
Carmelita, you don't
need to sacrifice anymore.
Ignacio and I found a way.
We will rescue Eduardo tomorrow night.
And we will wait for you and Maria.
At the end of the Lake of Tears.
Maria and Eduardo will elope too?
If we can take Maria
away from Don Alejandro,
her baby would be safe.
And I won't have to marry Leandro.
Are you coming with me, Carmelita?
Just promise me this.
That whatever happens...
You'll live.
And whatever happens,
I will never leave you.
Thank you, Don Alejandro.
Oh, by the way...
I heard the arranged marriage between Maria
and Gobernadorcillo Flores was called off.
Gobernadorcillo Flores
actually told me that.
He will be truly grateful
to have a wife like Maria.
Gobernadorcillo Flores knows
that my daughter is with child.
But he is still willing to
accept her as his bride.
On the condition
that the child will be aborted.
Do you...
Do you know a good midwife?
So, Don Alejandro still
plans to kill Maria's child!
My wife... knows a talented midwife.
From the North.
When...
When do you want to call them?
As soon as possible.
My daughter has been pregnant for a month.
Rest assured, Don Alejandro.
I will tell them to go to Laguna next week.
Good.
Come. Have a bite of food first.
Liar!
Even if Leandro and I were to get married,
he would still abort Maria's child
and marry her off to Governor Flores.
My God.
That can't be.
We can't wait any longer, Josefina.
You have to help us.
Help you with what?
Juanito and Eduardo will help
Eduardo escape prison tonight.
Maria and I will come with them.
You're eloping?!
That is too dangerous.
Josefina, this is the only way.
You are the only one
Father trusts right now.
Alright.
I'll find a way so that
Father would allow me to
come inside Maria's room.
I will help her escape.
This Wednesday, Aunt Rosario
will come and fetch Maria.
Help her set-up her room there.
Ate Maria won’t be going
to Laguna for two more days,
that's why we need to
sneak her out tonight.
I know you both have things to do.
Josefina, do your best
at the upcoming prayer for All Souls' Day.
Carmelita.
Do your best in preparing
for your upcoming wedding.
The agreed date is by the end of December.
Once everything is settled,
send me a letter with your address.
I will go there at once.
Thank you, Josefina.
Take care, both of you.
Go on, before the guards spot you.
Go!
Thank you so much, Josefina.
Will you really not stop
with this nonsense?!
Eduardo!
I don't know what to do with you anymore!
If not for Esmeralda,
I wouldn't know you are planning
to elope with these scums!
And you, Josefina.
I didn't expect you to
condone your sisters!
Father...
Please, forgive me.
Forgive me, Father.
We're sorry, Father.
I beg you, please, do not hurt them.
All you bring me is shame.
You two,
you shouldn't have
step foot into this place!
This transgression warrants death!
Take away the sisters from here!
- Father, we are begging you!
- Father...
Let go of me!
Father, please do not hurt them! Eduardo!
General Seleno.
Take that Alfonso first. He's
the root of all our problems!
Farewell to you,
Juanito Alfonso.
Father!
Eduardo!
Juanito!
Juanito is dead.
I'm sorry.
I can sense that
Juanito is still alive.
There are things
that cannot stay with us.
Let Juanito go.
Bad news.
Theresita is here in
San Alfonso with Sonya.
What?
She wants to plead
for Ignacio's case.
We have to stop her.
There is only one way
for you to be with your husband.
And that is death.
Don Alejandro!
The rebels attacked the plaza.
Miss Josefina was stabbed.
The mastermind behind all this...
The death of Josefina...
Was Juanito Alfonso.
Look at what
you've done, Carmelita!
You helped this scum escape!
You gave them the chance
to hurt your sister!
You need to marry Leandro.
If not, all I worked hard for
will be for nothing.